hi
did you know your health insurance
policy may
not cover advanced treatment methods
what do you mean by advanced treatment
methods does your health insurance
policy
have sub limits on the coverages for
these latest treatments where do you
find out all this information
let's find out in this video
advanced treatment methods are minimally
invasive
they have much lesser side effects
patients have
faster recovery rates and these
treatments
are very expensive some examples of
advanced treatment methods are robotic
surgeries
stem cell therapy oral chemotherapy
balloon sinuplasty and many many more
surgeries
as per a survey by 2023-2025
more than 50 percent of the surgeries
are going to be
robotic take a look
now your health insurance policy may
not cover these advanced treatment
methods
or there may be sub limits on the
coverages
on these latest treatments let's
understand this
with the help of an example here
let's say a person is hospitalized
for a major critical illness the cost
of such treatment for a major critical
illness can be very high
this person has a health insurance
policy
with a cover of rupees 10 lakhs and the
cost of treatment
for immunotherapy here it's a modern
treatment
is rupees 8 lakhs now let's see
how much gets settled by the health
insurance company
this slide shows the sub limits on the
modern treatments
which is applicable in this policy
on your extreme left is the sum insured
which is marked in red on your right
are the sub limits applicable on each
treatment
methods so against a total cover of
rupees 10 lakhs
the coverage available under this policy
for immunotherapy
is only rupees 4 lakhs similarly
for a rupees 25 lakhs insurance cover
the
coverage available for immunotherapy is
only
rupees 6 lakhs it means at the time of
climate settlement claim settlement
for immunotherapy treatment the health
insurance company
will pay only rupees 4 lakhs though you
have a high
total sum insurance of rupees 10 lakhs
available in the policy
the balance amount of rupees 4 lakhs
needs to be fully borne by the client
so what's the point in having such a
high
insurance cover
in another example here the health
insurance
company in its policy wordings clearly
states
that the coverage available for all
modern treatments
is capped at 50 percent of the total
insurance cover available in the policy
so purchasing a health insurance policy
just based on premiums may not be a good
idea
next time you are purchasing a health
insurance
or your porting your existing policy to
a new service provider
these are some important point that you
need to check
so where do you find all this important
information
this information can be found out in a
document called as policy wordings
or policy terms and conditions
this information is not available or may
not be available
in the policy brochure so at the time of
purchase
make sure you check both the policy
brochure
along with policy boardings in case you
have
any clarifications regarding this you
can always call me
that is insurance man at nine eight four
five
double three four triple zero and
if you found this information useful
please like share and subscribe
to my channel thank you